soundblaster.com 2011-05-27

# Creative Worldwide - Sound Blaster, MP3 Players, Speakers, Web Cameras and more.

Last revised 05 September, 2007

Creative Technology Ltd and its subsidiary and affiliated companies (or "Creative", "we" "our" and "us") adheres strictly to best privacy practices to ensure that your privacy is respected and all personal information you provide to us is kept confidential. 

Our privacy policy discloses our privacy practices for handling online personal and non-personal information, and is meant to comply with applicable local laws and regulations. Please read this privacy policy carefully before you use any of Creative's web sites ("Site(s)"). By using or accessing the Sites, you are accepting this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use at any time. We encourage you to refer to this Privacy Policy on an ongoing basis so that you are aware of the current terms.

_**What information do we collect?**_

 _i) Non-sensitive Information_   
As a visitor to our Sites, you can engage in many activities without providing any personal information. However, we do collect and aggregate information pertaining to the web pages visited and general usage patterns through the use of "cookies" as described below. Such information is not linked to any sensitive information. The non-sensitive information we collect helps us identify the most popular areas of our Sites and determines the effectiveness of our promotional activities. 

* Cookies   
Cookies are text files that a web server can store on a user's hard disk. Cookies allow a web site to store information on a user's machine and retrieve it later. Cookies collect information like IP addresses, operating systems and browser software, but they do not collect any personal information. Cookies enable us to customize your experience and provide greater convenience at our Sites. Creative will not allow any third party to use cookies to track or collect any personally identifiable information from you. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies; you should refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. You may be able to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings on your browser. 

_ii) Sensitive Information_  
You may have the opportunity to participate in any of the following activities at some Creative Sites, including but not limited to: product registration, surveys/polls/contests, software downloads, product registration, online shopping, newsletter subscription or forum participation. These activities may require the collection of sensitive personal information including: your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, credit card details, and/or information about your interests in the use of various products, programs and services. Such data collected may be combined with the information you provided when you registered the ownership of your Creative products. Creative is committed to safeguarding your personal information and will only use such information to better understand your needs and to provide you with better service.

**_How may we use the information?_**  
Creative will not sell, rent, loan or lease your personal information to others unless we have your express permission or are required by law to do so. Creative will not use or share the personally identifiable information that you provide to us online in ways unrelated to those described herein without first letting you know and offering you a choice to opt out.

If you have any problems exercising your choice to opt out, please [contact us](http://www.creative.com/privacy/contactus/).

Because Creative operates globally, we may need to share your personal information with our worldwide business units. We will only share your information with other Creative entities (including subsidiaries and affiliates) and/or business partners who are acting on our behalf to provide the necessary service or information requested by you, to consolidate data storage, or to simplify the management of customer information. Such Creative entities and/or business partners are governed by our Privacy Policy with respect to the use of this data and are bound by appropriate confidentiality agreements.

In addition, for us to serve you better, we may use your personal information for the following purposes, including but not limited to:

__i) The Creative Online Store__  
To process your order, we will ask you for your personal information such as: name, e-mail address, delivery address, telephone number and credit card information.

_ii) Online Registration_  
You can register your Creative product using an online registration application or via [creative.com/register](http://www.creative.com/register/). By registering your Creative product, you will be eligible to receive product support. The level of support available is dependent on the type of Creative product purchased. For more details, visit [creative.com/support](http://www.creative.com/support/). Personal information collected from online registration will be used to improve our products and services. Creative's internal reports will not contain personal individual data. With your permission, we will send you information about new products or services from Creative.

_iii) Surveys/Polls/Contests/Promotions_  
From time to time, our Sites may request information from you via surveys/polls/contests/promotions and other marketing activities. Participation in these activities is completely voluntary and you have a choice whether or not to disclose any information. Information requested may include contact information; such as your name and your shipping address to notify the winner(s) and demographic information; such as your age, for eligibility purposes. Survey information will be used for the purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of our Sites.

_iv) Mailing List_  
Creative may occasionally send you marketing materials or product information via e-mail. Your e-mail address will only be used for these purposes and will never be shared with unaffiliated third parties without your consent. Where applicable, we will follow all local requirements, such as allowing you to opt in before receiving unsolicited e-mails. You have the right to opt out from receiving such electronic communications from us at anytime.

__*Important Note for European Visitors__  
For visitors from the European Economic Area, please note that Creative may transfer your personally identifiable data outside the European Economic Area for use for any of the purposes described herein. By using our Site and providing us with your personal data, you consent to such transfer of your personal data.

**_How do we protect sensitive information?_**  
To prevent unauthorized access to our database, and to ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard sensitive information. We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption on web pages where personal information is required. 

**_Information from Children_**  
Creative will never knowingly collect sensitive information from children under 16 for marketing purposes. If we learn that personal information has been submitted to us by children under 16, we will delete such information from our files. Minors under the age of 16 should ask their parents or guardians for permission before submitting any personal information to anyone over the Internet.

**_Third Party Web Sites_**   
Please note that our Privacy Policy only applies to sites controlled by Creative. Links to third party web sites are provided solely as a convenience to you. You are advised to check the privacy policies and terms of use of those sites before providing your personal information to them. Creative has not reviewed all of these third party web sites, does not control and is not responsible for any of these sites, their contents or their privacy policies and terms of use. Creative does not endorse or make any representations about these other sites, or any information, products or other materials that may be found there. Access to and use of such other web sites is at the user's own risk and subject to any terms and conditions applicable to such access/use. 

**_Information requests_**   
You are entitled to ask for a copy of the personal information we hold about you at any time (for which we may charge a small administration fee). We will correct any inaccuracies in your personal information at your request.

**_Contacting Us_**   
We value your opinions. If you have any questions or comments about our Privacy Policy or questions or concerns about the use of your personal information, please [contact us](http://www.creative.com/privacy/contactus/). You can send your request to:

 **Asia, Oceania, Middle East & Africa:**  
Data Privacy (Legal Department)  
Creative Technology Ltd  
31, International Business Park  
Creative Resource  
Singapore 609921  
Singapore 

**Europe:**  
Data Privacy (Legal Department)  
Creative Labs (Irl) Ltd.  
Ballycoolin Business Park  
Blanchardstown  
Dublin 15  
Ireland  
Registered in Ireland (No. 207960) 

**Americas:**  
Data Privacy (Legal Department)  
Creative Labs, Inc.  
1901 McCarthy Blvd.  
Milpitas, CA 95035  
USA  

Return to previous page
